const quizData = [
    //  phile (love) file starts from here
    
    {
        "question": "What is ASTROPHILE characterized by?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Obsession with writing",
            "Person interested in astronomy",
            "Obsession with stealing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Person interested in astronomy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is AUDIOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "A person who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Someone who loves beards"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A person who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does AUTOPHILE involve?",
        "options": [
            "A person who loves being alone",
            "Obsession with books",
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Obsession with trying drugs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A person who loves being alone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is BIBLIOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Someone who loves novelty and new things",
            "Someone who loves beards",
            "Someone who usually collects books"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who usually collects books"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does CHINOPHILE denote?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "A person who loves being alone",
            "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics",
            "Someone who finds comfort in cold weather"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who finds comfort in cold weather"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does CLINOPHILE denote?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "A person who loves being alone",
            "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics",
            "Lying in bed or reclining"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Lying in bed or reclining"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is CYNOPHILE characterized by?",
        "options": [
            "Obsession with books",
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Someone who loves novelty and new things",
            "Obsession with trying drugs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves dogs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does ERGOPHILE refer to?",
        "options": [
            "A person who loves work",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Obsession with stealing",
            "Someone who loves beards"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A person who loves work"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is HELIOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "A person who loves being alone",
            "Someone who loves the sun",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Someone who loves beards"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves the sun"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does NEOPHILE entail?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves the sun",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Someone who loves novelty and new things",
            "Obsession with books"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves novelty and new things"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is NYCTOPHILE characterized by?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Someone who loves night and darkness",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Obsession with writing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves night and darkness"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does PEDOPHILE involve?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves beards",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Someone who is sexually attracted to children",
            "Obsession with books"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who is sexually attracted to children"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is PHOTOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "A person who loves being alone",
            "Someone who loves the sun",
            "Someone who loves natural light",
            "Someone who usually collects books"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves natural light"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does POGONOPHILE refer to?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves natural light",
            "Someone who loves beards",
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves beards"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is RETROPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves beards",
            "Someone who loves aesthetics from the past",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Obsession with writing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves aesthetics from the past"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does TECHNOPHILE denote?",
        "options": [
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who is fond of technology",
            "Someone who loves night and darkness",
            "Someone who loves dogs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who is fond of technology"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is THEOPHILE characterized by?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Someone who loves the sun",
            "Someone who loves God",
            "Someone who loves dogs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves God"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does TOBACCO-PHILE refer to?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Someone who loves tobacco",
            "Someone who loves night and darkness",
            "Someone who loves dogs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves tobacco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is XENOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves natural light",
            "Someone who loves beards",
            "Someone who loves foreign things",
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves foreign things"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does AESTHETOPHILE entail?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves foreign things",
            "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Obsession with writing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is CRYPTOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics",
            "Someone who loves hidden or secret things",
            "A person who loves work",
            "A person who loves being alone"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves hidden or secret things"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does CRYPTOMANIA denote?",
        "options": [
            "Obsession with trying drugs",
            "Obsession with writing",
            "Obsession with hidden or secret things or obsessive interest with cryptocurrency",
            "A person who loves work"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Obsession with hidden or secret things or obsessive interest with cryptocurrency"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is GAZOPHILE characterized by?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves hidden or secret things",
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Who prefers living in areas with abundant light , such as sunlight",
            "A person who loves work"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Who prefers living in areas with abundant light , such as sunlight"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is GRAPHOMANIA?",
        "options": [
            "Obsession with writing",
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who loves dogs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Obsession with writing"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is KINESIOPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "Someone who loves movement or physical activity",
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "A person who loves work"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves movement or physical activity"
    },

    {
        "question": "What does NUMISMATOPHILE refer to?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Someone who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who loves collecting coins or currencies"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves collecting coins or currencies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is OMNIPHILE?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves everything or has a wide range of interests",
            "Someone who loves night and darkness",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who loves dogs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who loves everything or has a wide range of interests"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does PAEDOPHILE involve?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who is sexually attracted to young children",
            "Someone who loves beauty or aesthetics"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Someone who is sexually attracted to young children"
    },



    // Mania file starts from here
        {
            "question": "What does ABLUTOMANIA refer to?",
            "options": [
                "Desire to be in open places",
                "Obsession with England and English",
                "Obsession with flowers",
                "Mania for washing oneself"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mania for washing oneself"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does VERBOMANIA refer to?",
        "options": [
            "Inordinate attachment to foreign objects",
            "Insane fondness for animals",
            "Craze for using words",
            "A person who loves accurately reproduced recorded sounds"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Craze for using words"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does XENOMANIA entail?",
        "options": [
            "Insane fondness for animals",
            "Inordinate attachment to foreign things",
            "Person interested in astronomy",
            "Someone who loves novelty and new things"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Inordinate attachment to foreign things"
    },
        {
            "question": "What does AGROMANIA entail?",
            "options": [
                "Intense desire to be in open places",
                "Obsession with England and English",
                "Obsession with flowers",
                "Obsession with issuing old marriage proposals"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Intense desire to be in open places"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does ANTHOMANIA describe?",
            "options": [
                "Dancing mania or frenzy",
                "Obsession with flowers",
                "Abnormal craving for alcohol",
                "Mania for money"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with flowers"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is BIBLIOMANIA characterized by?",
            "options": [
                "Obsession with books",
                "Obsession with stealing",
                "Minor mania",
                "Belief that one is a god"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with books"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does CACODEMOMANIA involve?",
            "options": [
                "Desire to return to familiar places",
                "Delusion of being inhabited by an evil spirit",
                "Obsession with trying drugs",
                "Craze for starting fires"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Delusion of being inhabited by an evil spirit"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is CHOREOMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Intense desire for water",
                "Dancing mania or dance",
                "Obsession with oneself",
                "Obsession with stealing"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Dancing mania or dance"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does DIPSOMANIA denote?",
            "options": [
                "Abnormal craving for alcohol",
                "Mania for money",
                "Craze for technology",
                "Desire to be in open places"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Abnormal craving for alcohol"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is EGOMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Obsession with trying drugs",
                "Obsession with oneself",
                "Desire to return to familiar places",
                "Inational propensity for spending money"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with oneself"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does GAMOMANIA refer to?",
            "options": [
                "Desire to be in open places",
                "Obsession with issuing odd marriage proposals",
                "Intense desire for water",
                "Obsession with books"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with issuing odd marriage proposals"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does HYDROMANIA entail?",
            "options": [
                "Intense desire for water",
                "Obsession with flowers",
                "Belief that one is a god",
                "Obsession with England and English"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Intense desire for water"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is HYPOMANIA characterized by?",
            "options": [
                "Mania for money",
                "Minor mania",
                "Obsession with trying drugs",
                "Dancing mania or frenzy"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Minor mania"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does KLEPTOMANIA involve?",
            "options": [
                "Dancing mania or frenzy",
                "Desire to return to familiar places",
                "Obsession with stealing",
                "Obsession with books"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with stealing"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is NOSTOMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Abnormal desire for poisons",
                "Desire to return to familiar places",
                "Craze for technology",
                "Obsession with trying drugs"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Desire to return to familiar places"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does PHARMACOMANIA denote?",
            "options": [
                "Obsession with trying drugs",
                "Craze for starting fires",
                "Obsession with oneself",
                "Mania for washing oneself"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Obsession with trying drugs"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is PLUTOMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Desire to be in open places",
                "Mania for money",
                "Craze for technology",
                "Obsession with England and English"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Mania for money"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does PYROMANIA involve?",
            "options": [
                "Craze for starting fires",
                "Obsession with trying drugs",
                "Belief that one is a god",
                "Obsession with issuing old marriage proposals"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Craze for starting fires"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is SQUANDEROMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Obsession with oneself",
                "Inational propensity for spending money",
                "Obsession with books",
                "Abnormal desire for poisons"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Inational propensity for spending money"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is TECHOMANIA characterized by?",
            "options": [
                "Mania for money",
                "Craze for technology",
                "Obsession with England and English",
                "Desire to be in open places"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Craze for technology"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does THEOMANIA refer to?",
            "options": [
                "Obsession with flowers",
                "Belief that one is a god",
                "Obsession with stealing",
                "Dancing mania or frenzy"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Belief that one is a god"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is TOXICOMANIA?",
            "options": [
                "Craze for starting fires",
                "Obsession with books",
                "Abnormal desire for poisons",
                "Obsession with trying drugs"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": "Abnormal desire for poisons"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is MELLOMANIA?",
        "options": [
            "Someone who loves dogs",
            "Obsession with melodious music",
            "A person who loves work",
            "Someone who loves night and darkness"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Obsession with melodious music"
    },



    // Antonyms file starts from here
        
   

    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - DISTANT",
        options: ["Remote", "Near", "Isolated", "Removed"],
        correctAnswer: "Near"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - IGNORANT",
        options: ["Learned", "Informed", "Aware", "Uninformed"],
        correctAnswer: "Learned"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - PARTNER",
        options: ["Opponent", "Collaborator", "Ally", "Friend"],
        correctAnswer: "Opponent"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - COMPLEX",
        options: ["Simple", "Basic", "Intricate", "Complicated"],
        correctAnswer: "Simple"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - VALIANT",
        options: ["Cowardly", "Fearful", "Brave", "Courageous"],
        correctAnswer: "Cowardly"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - NARROW",
        options: ["Wide", "Broad", "Limited", "Compact"],
        correctAnswer: "Wide"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - FLIMSY",
        options: ["Strong", "Sturdy", "Fragile", "Resilient"],
        correctAnswer: "Strong"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - DEFENCE",
        options: ["Offence", "Attack", "Aggression", "Counterattack"],
        correctAnswer: "Offence"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - STABLE",
        options: ["Shaky", "Unsteady", "Fragile", "Rocky"],
        correctAnswer: "Shaky"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - BLAME",
        options: ["Praise", "Commendation", "Approval", "Approbation"],
        correctAnswer: "Praise"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - RIDICULOUS",
        options: ["Reasonable / Logical", "Sensible", "Plausible", "Cogent"],
        correctAnswer: "Reasonable / Logical"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - LEARNED",
        options: ["Ignorant", "Uninformed", "Illiterate", "Naive"],
        correctAnswer: "Ignorant"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - OPPONENT",
        options: ["Partner", "Supporter", "Ally", "Assistant"],
        correctAnswer: "Partner"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - SIMPLE",
        options: ["Complex", "Intricate", "Difficult", "Advanced"],
        correctAnswer: "Complex"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - COWARDLY",
        options: ["Valiant", "Brave", "Fearless", "Daring"],
        correctAnswer: "Valiant"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - WIDE",
        options: ["Narrow", "Constricted", "Restricted", "Slim"],
        correctAnswer: "Narrow"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - STRONG",
        options: ["Weak", "Frail", "Vulnerable", "Delicate"],
        correctAnswer: "Weak"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - OFFENCE",
        options: ["Defence", "Protection", "Guard", "Safety"],
        correctAnswer: "Defence"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - SHAKY",
        options: ["Stable", "Secure", "Firm", "Steadfast"],
        correctAnswer: "Stable"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - PRAISE",
        options: ["Blame", "Censure", "Criticism", "Reproach"],
        correctAnswer: "Blame"
    },
    {
        question: "Select the most appropriate Antonym of the given word - REASONABLE / LOGICAL",
        options: ["Ridiculous", "Absurd", "Illogical", "Unreasonable"],
        correctAnswer: "Ridiculous"
    }
];


let currentQuestion = 0;
let score = 0;



// ...

let totalQuizTimer;
let questionTimer;
let totalSecondsRemaining = 600; // 10 minutes
let secondsRemaining = 20;

function startQuiz() {
    startTotalTimer();
    showQuestion();
}

function startTotalTimer() {
    totalQuizTimer = setInterval(updateTotalTimer, 1000);
}

function updateTotalTimer() {
    const totalTimerElement = document.getElementById('total-timer');

    if (totalSecondsRemaining > 0) {
        totalSecondsRemaining--;
        const minutes = Math.floor(totalSecondsRemaining / 60);
        const seconds = totalSecondsRemaining % 60;
        totalTimerElement.textContent = `Total Time Remaining: ${minutes}:${seconds < 10 ? '0' : ''}${seconds}`;
    } else {
        clearInterval(totalQuizTimer);
        totalTimerElement.textContent = 'Total Time Expired!';
        endQuiz();
    }
}

function startQuestionTimer() {
    questionTimer = setInterval(updateQuestionTimer, 1000);
}

function updateQuestionTimer() {

    const timerElement = document.getElementById('question-timer');

    if (secondsRemaining > 0) {
        secondsRemaining--;
        timerElement.textContent = `Question Time Remaining: ${secondsRemaining} seconds`;
    } else {
        clearInterval(questionTimer);
        timerElement.textContent = 'Time Expired!';
        handleTimeExpired();
    }
}

function handleTimeExpired() {
    document.getElementById('feedback').textContent = 'Time Expired!';
    setTimeout(nextQuestion, 1500); // Move to the next question after 1.5 seconds
}


function startQuiz() {
    startTotalTimer();
    showQuestion();
}

function showQuestion() {
    const questionContainer = document.getElementById('question-container');
    const optionsContainer = document.getElementById('options-container');
    const feedback = document.getElementById('feedback');

    // Reset the question timer and seconds remaining
    secondsRemaining = 20;
    startQuestionTimer();

    questionContainer.innerHTML = quizData[currentQuestion].question;
    optionsContainer.innerHTML = '';

    quizData[currentQuestion].options.forEach((option, index) => {
        const button = document.createElement('button');
        button.textContent = option;
        button.onclick = () => checkAnswer(option);
        optionsContainer.appendChild(button);

        // Highlight the correct option
        if (option === quizData[currentQuestion].correctAnswer) {
            button.dataset.correct = true;
        }
    });

    feedback.textContent = '';
}


function checkAnswer(selectedOption) {
    clearInterval(questionTimer); // Clear the existing question timer

    const optionsContainer = document.getElementById('options-container');
    const options = optionsContainer.getElementsByTagName('button');

    for (const optionButton of options) {
        optionButton.disabled = true; // Disable all options after an answer is selected
        if (optionButton.textContent === selectedOption) {
            if (selectedOption !== quizData[currentQuestion].correctAnswer) {
                optionButton.style.backgroundColor = '#e32929'; // Highlight the chosen wrong answer
            }
        }
        if (optionButton.textContent === quizData[currentQuestion].correctAnswer) {
            optionButton.style.backgroundColor = '#4cd95a'; // Highlight the correct answer
        }
    }

    if (selectedOption === quizData[currentQuestion].correctAnswer) {
        score++;
        document.getElementById('feedback').innerHTML = '<span style="color: #67cc56;">Correct!</span>';
        setTimeout(nextQuestion, 1500); // Move to the next question after 1.5 seconds
    } else {
        document.getElementById('feedback').innerHTML = 'Wrong answer. The correct answer is: <span style="color: #d40000;">' + quizData[currentQuestion].correctAnswer + '</span>';
        setTimeout(nextQuestion, 2500); // Move to the next question after 2.5 seconds
    }

    document.getElementById('next-btn').disabled = false;
}


function nextQuestion() {
    currentQuestion++;
    if (currentQuestion < quizData.length) {
        showQuestion();
        document.getElementById('next-btn').disabled = true;
    } else {
        endQuiz();
    }
}

// ...

function endQuiz() {
    const quizContainer = document.getElementById('quiz-container');
    quizContainer.innerHTML = `<h2>Quiz Completed!</h2>
<p>Your Score: ${score*2} out of ${quizData.length*2} </p> <p> Thanks For Completing <br> Wanna try out other Quiz ! </p> <br> <a href="index.html"> Yes </a>`;
}
startQuiz();


    // Toggle responsive navbar on small screens
function toggleNavbar() {
    var x = document.getElementById("myNavbar");
    if (x.className.indexOf("responsive") === -1) {
        x.className += " responsive";
    } else {
        x.className = x.className.replace(" responsive", "");
    }
}


